Yannis Wen

J +33604032989 — ▼yannis.wen@gmail.com — filinkedin.com/in/yannis-w/ — filinkedin.com/in/yannis-w/

Summary — Senior Data Analyst from the adtech industry with **4 years of work experience**. Expert in uncovering insights behind users' behaviors and turning them into business value. Comfortable working at the interface of multiple functions such as Product, Sales, and Marketing.

Skills

Programming Python, HTML
Dashboarding Tableau, Plotly Dash
Cloud Google BigQuery, Azure

Data Querying & ETL SQL, Python (Pandas, NumPy)
Others Excel, Powerpoint

Experience

CRITEO Apr 2024 – Present

Senior Data Analyst, AGENCY CURATION REVENUE

Mission: Enhance deal-based trading of CRITEO SSP

- Analytics lead for the Curation product of CRITEO SSP
- Grew the Commerce Audiences product from 6k€ to 18k€ of monthly revenue
- Implemented a GenAI audience recommendation tool to streamline the sales process of deals (20 weekly users)
- Acted as data & business expert in Product kick-offs
- Developed NLP method to find best prospects for deals among CRITEO advertisers
- Forecasted revenue for pitches of retailers such as Currys, THG, ASDA that would generate 2M€ in yearly revenue
- Established processes to collect data in Salesforce and ingest it in HDFS (40 users)
- Set up an alerting script to flag issues on audiences included in deals
- Delivered sales enablement dashboards to track progress and historical performances (100 views/month)

CRITEO Nov 2021 – Mar 2024

Data Analyst, MEDIA OWNERS

Mission: Optimise the monetisation of CRITEO publishers in Europe

- Conducted A/B test analyses to optimize the monetization of german publishers by 5%
- Developed innovative, data-backed pitch material to help close publisher contracts
- Shipped dashboards to monitor the adoption of new CRITEO products with publishers
- Automated repetitive analyses in a Slack bot for commercial stakeholders to be autonomous (200 usages/month)
- Provided day-to-day operational support through data (300 issues solved)

Mars & Co. Mar 2019 – Aug 2019

Data Science Intern, MARKETING

- Designed and implemented several statistical marketing attribution models with Python (*Shapley values, Markov chains, Linear model*)
- Worked on the large online sales data of the french theme park Futuroscope

Education

Edinburgh University 2021

MSc in Business Analytics

- Graduated with Distinction
- Dissertation: Using NLP sentiment analysis to identify which writing style performs best for marketing emails of hotels

École Polytechnique, Paris

2017 - 2020

Engineering degree (Diplôme d'ingénieur)

- Majors: Computer Science and Economics

Languages

French: Native English: Fluent

German: Intermediate